<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ethereal</string>
    <string name="quote">"It's okay to be less than perfect."</string>
    <string name="actidesc">"Things you can do to boost your mental state are referred to as mental health activities. Collaborating in mental health activities can improve your overall health, well-being and as well as your sense of inner peace."</string>
    <string name="mediactidesc">"If stress has you anxious, tense and worried, consider trying meditation. Spending even a few minutes in meditation can restore your calm and inner peace."</string>
    <string name="healthactisdesc">Mental health is vital to overall personal wellness. It\'s our emotional psychological and social well-being. Here are some health courses that can help to improve your overall psychological well-being.</string>
    <string name="forgotdesc">"We will send an email to your registered ID with \ninstructions to reset your password."</string>
    <string name="therapistquote">"The role of the therapist is to reflect the being/accepting self\n that was never allowed to be in the borderline."\n― Michael Adzema."</string>
    <string name="i_already"><u>I already have an account</u></string>
    <string name="crisis">Are you in crisis?</string>
    <string name="panictext">You are not alone. Help is just a\ncall away.</string>
    <string name="panicdesc">If you are dealing with abuse, trauma or crisis, Ethereal is not enough. It is important that you talk to a person you feel safe sharing what you are dealing with. If there is no one, call one of the helplines below. Things will get better.</string>
    <string name="health_points">Based on your overall health test,\npoints you have secured is 84.</string>
    <string name="welcomedesc1">Get help with common mental health\nproblems such as stress, anxiety, depression\nand panic attacks. In a safer space.</string>
    <string name="welcomedesc2">Discover and plan the activities that you find\nmost useful. We will remind you beforehand\nand help you self-reflect afterwards.</string>
    <string name="welcomedesc3">Stay motivated by logging your mood, stress,\nmindfulness or sleep seeing these changes\nover time.</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="currenttime">0:00</string>
    <string name="totaltime">0:00</string>
    <string name="course1day1">With today\'s tumultuous and uncharted climate, a certain amount of worry and anxiety are normal. While we use these terms interchangeably, they are entirely different animals — and they have different implications for health and well-being.
\n\nIf people aren\'t a little bit worried right now, that\'s a problem, says Jeffrey Devore, MSW, a behavioral health social worker at Henry Ford Health. Worry and anxiety fall on a spectrum. They\'re different states, but they\'re also interrelated.
    \n\n<b>Worry Versus Anxiety</b>
        \n\nChances are good that you regularly experience some level of worry (or even anxiety). But what do these terms really mean? Both states are marked by a sense of concern, disquiet and possibly stress. But they\'re not the same.
        \n\nHere are five key differences between worry and anxiety:
        \n\n<b>Worry tends to reside in our minds.\nAnxiety affects both body and mind.</b>
\n\nEveryday worries take place in your thoughts, while anxiety often manifests physically in the body, Devore explains. You might feel faint or lightheaded. Some people even hyperventilate. People who are anxious are also more likely to suffer from digestive problems like nausea, indigestion and irritable bowel syndrome.
   \n\n<b>Worry is specific.\nAnxiety is more generalized.</b>
    \n\nWhether you\'re fixating on your odds of contracting the coronavirus or trying to figure out how you\'ll be able to homeschool three children, worry is distinct and concrete. Anxiety is generally vague. You feel unsettled, but you can\'t pinpoint what you\'re really anxious about — and that can make problem-solving difficult.
    \n\n<b>Worry is grounded in reality.\nAnxiety is marked by catastrophic thinking.</b>
    \n\nThere\'s a logical component to worry. Your brain is trying to make sense of a real and present danger. Worrying when your fears are actionable makes sense. It\’s worry that can lead you to take coronavirus precautions, like washing your hands and wearing a mask. Anxiety, on the other hand, overestimates risk. So if the real risk of a negative outcome is 10%, someone who is anxious may perceive the risk closer to 70%, Devore explains. To make matters worse, people who are suffering from anxiety may underestimate their ability to cope with a negative outcome.
    \n\n<b>Worry is temporary.\nAnxiety is longstanding.</b>
    \n\nWorry is usually short term. There\'s a concerning situation (like COVID-19) and you worry about it. Worry prods you to use problem-solving skills to address your concerns. Anxiety is persistent, even when concerns are unrealistic. It often compromises your ability to function.
    \n\n<b>Worry doesn\'t impair function.\nAnxiety does.</b>
    \n\nYou probably won\'t be forced to take a sick day due to worries about finances or weight gain. Anxiety, however, seeps into your psyche and can make it difficult to focus and get stuff done.
        \n\nWorry and anxiety are not all bad. In fact, they can motivate change, Devore says. The key is using problem-solving skills to address what you\'re worried about and reduce the risk of your fears being realized.
    </string>
    <string name="course1day2">All anxiety disorders, including panic disorder, involve some degree of anxiety and nervousness. Anxiety is an inner state that includes feelings of dread, worry, fear, stress, and apprehension. For people with panic disorder, the impact of anxiety is typically experienced on mental, emotional, and even physical levels.
    \n\nA particularly unpleasant experience of anxiety-related physical sensations can come in the form of a panic attack, the main symptom of panic disorder. These attacks are characterized by distressing physical feelings, such as chest pain, accelerated heart rate, shaking, trembling, and shortness of breath.
    \n\nAnxiety can become such a regular part of your life that you may not even notice how it is physically affecting you. For example, anxiety tends to increase bodily tension, leading to tightness in specific areas, such as the back, neck, and shoulders.
    \n\nOn the other hand, you may be well aware of how panic and anxiety are putting strains on your body, but are struggling to cope with the physical symptoms of panic disorder. Luckily, there are some steps you can take to manage your difficult somatic symptoms. Listed below are ways you can manage the physical symptoms of panic and anxiety:
    \n\n<b>Change Your Mind</b>
    \n\nPart of the fear and discomfort associated with the physical symptoms of panic disorder is caused by one\’s thoughts. For example, when feeling anxiety-related symptoms of excessive sweating, trembling, or choking sensations, people may become fearful that they will lose control or that others are judging their reactions.
    \n\nDuring a panic attack, a person may feel afraid of the consequences of the physical symptoms, fearing that it will lead to a medical emergency. Such fears only heighten this sense of anxiety, possibly causing more intense panic and anxiety.
    \n\nOne way to more effectively deal with your physical symptoms is to work on the way you are responding to them. Some things you can do include:
    \n\n<b>Self-reflection</b> such as journaling or mood and anxiety tracking, which can help you in exploring your automatic reactions to your symptoms and determine ways to change them.
    \n\n<b>Affirmations</b> are another way you can work towards shifting your thoughts.
    \n\n<b>Take Care of Yourself Physically</b>
    \n\nStudies have shown that nutrition and exercise can impact your experience with panic disorder symptoms. To better manage the physical symptoms of panic and anxiety, consider making some healthy lifestyle changes.
    \n\n<b>Avoid certain foods or drinks</b> that may trigger or worsen anxiety. For instance, an overabundance of certain foods and substances, including caffeine and sugar, can aggravate feelings of anxiety.
    \n\n<b>Physical exercise</b> can help relieve stress and tension felt throughout the body, increase energy levels, and improve mood.
    \n\n<b>Stress-reducing relaxation exercises</b> such as yoga and meditation can help you learn how to control your body sensations and remain calm in the face of anxiety.
    \n\n<b>Bring Your Awareness Elsewhere</b>
    \n\nWhen physical symptoms become overwhelming, it can help to adjust your focus to more pleasant activities. When anxious physical sensations are on the rise, try to redirect your attention to something else. Think about what activities you enjoy and could quickly change your focus.
    \n\nRegardless of what activities you choose, the point is to channel your excess energy into something that you find fun and soothing.
    \n\n<b>Seek Treatment</b>
    \n\nIf you are experiencing the physical symptoms of panic disorder, panic attacks, and anxiety, it is important to seek help. A physician or qualified mental health specialist will be able to assist you in coping with your physical symptoms.
    \n\nTreatment will involve getting the right diagnosis, participating in a treatment plan, and following-up with your doctor\’s recommendations. By getting the help you need, you can anticipate learning how to effectively manage the physical symptoms of panic and anxiety.</string>
    <string name="course1day3"><b>Start Challenging Your Worries</b>
    \n\nWriting your thoughts down on paper can have a dramatic impact because it allows you to see what you are actually thinking about. It can give you a realization that most of your thoughts seem extreme and unlikely to happen.
    \n\nThere are 5 steps to challenge your worries:
    \n\n<b>1. Build Awareness</b>
    \n\n<b>2. Write Down Your Thoughts</b>
    \n\n<b>3. Identify Thinking Style</b>
    \n\n<b>4. Challenege Your Thoughts</b>
    \n\n<b>5. Brainstorm Solutions</b></string>
    <string name="course1day4"><b>Positive Beliefs About Worrying</b>
    \n\n1. It motivates me to do things and solve problems.
    \n\n2. It helps me cope with negative feelings by preparing for the worst in advance.
    \n\n3. It stops bad things from happening.
    \n\n4. It shows I care.
    \n\n<b>Negative Beliefs About Worrying</b>
    \n\n1. I have no control over my worry.
    \n\n2. Worry will make me lose my mind.
    \n\n3. It will never stop, worry controls me.
    \n\n4. I can\'t focus on anything my (current) worry.</string>
    <string name="course1day5"><b>How to deal with uncertainty</b>
    \n\nThere is only so much you can control in life. Unexpected events will occur, and when they do, there are a few ways you can prepare to face uncertainty:
        \n\n<b>1. Build Your Tolerance</b>\n\nWe navigate uncertainty every day, like driving to work when we might not make it there safely. Acknowledging these every day uncertainties that we usually gloss over — and focusing on the fact that you still went about your life — can build your tolerance for more significant uncertainties, says Gertrude Lyons, Ed.D., a psychologist. If uncertainty is causing anxiety or depression, cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) can also help build your tolerance and reduce stress or worry.
    \n\n<b>2. Practice Mindfulness</b>\n\nA 2008 study of people who were unemployed found that mindfulness reduced suffering caused by uncertainty. Lyons recommends this approach: go through each of your five senses, focusing on three sensations you\'re experiencing. For example, what are three things you can feel right now? Three things you hear? When you start worrying about the uncertainties of the world, you can interrupt your thoughts with this routine. It can help ground you in the present moment and the certainties that do surround you.
    \n\n<b>3. Follow A Schedule</b>\n\nThe physiological consequences of stress can cause changes to your sleep and eating patterns. To counteract that, sticking to a schedule, including going to bed at the same time each day, is important during uncertain times, says Patel-Dunn. Having this routine can also give you a much-needed sense of structure and control when you\'re otherwise lacking it.
    \n\n<b>4. Let Go And Focus On Things You Can Control</b>\n\nAn unwillingness to experience anxiety or an intolerance to anxiety can often lead to additional suffering, Sinclair says. That\'s what we see now with people constantly googling, checking the news, or stockpiling supplies: it\'s trying to fight uncertainty in ways that ultimately increase anxiety or create cultures of fear. Instead, step back, unplug and focus on the things you can control — like your work, family time, and daily routine. </string>
    <string name="course1day6">Summary</string>
    <string name="course2day1"><b>What is Self Esteem?</b>
        \n\nSelf-esteem refers to a person\’s overall sense of his or her value or worth. It can be considered a sort of measure of how much a person values, approves of, appreciates, prizes, or likes him or herself
        \n\nAccording to self-esteem expert Morris Rosenberg, self-esteem is quite simply one\’s attitude toward oneself (1965). He described it as a favourable or unfavourable attitude toward the self.
        \n\nVarious factors believed to influence our self-esteem include:
        \n\n<b>1. Genetics</b>
        \n\n<b>2. Personality</b>
        \n\n<b>3. Life experiences</b>
        \n\n<b>4. Age</b>
        \n\n<b>5. Health</b>
        \n\n<b>6. Thoughts</b>
        \n\n<b>7. Social circumstances</b>
        \n\n<b>8. The reactions of others</b>
        \n\n<b>9. Comparing the self to others</b>
        \n\nAn important note is that self-esteem is not fixed. It is malleable and measurable, meaning we can test for and improve upon it.
        \n\n<b>What is Low Self Esteem?</b>
        \n\nLow self-esteem is when someone lacks confidence about who they are and what they can do. They often feel incompetent, unloved, or inadequate. People who struggle with low self-esteem are consistently afraid about making mistakes or letting other people down.

    </string>
    <string name="course2day2"><b>5 Steps To Change Your Thinking</b>
        \n\nOur thoughts create our feelings. Changing our thoughts changes how we feel.
        \n\nThis simple and yet challenging formula is what will turn these Cognitive Distortions around. The strategies outlined below challenge each one so that you can begin to think more effectively and realistically. As you practice these, you\’ll find yourself feeling better – about yourself and others.
        \n\n<b>Step 1: Identify Your Distortions</b>
        \n\nKeep a journal. As you become familiar with the 10 Cognitive Distortions, notice which ones you seem to favour. Writing down your thoughts and the corresponding distortions in your journal help you keep track of what you\’re thinking about and how you\’re feeling.
        \n\n<b>Step 2: Challenge Your Thinking</b>
        \n\nIt\’s important to challenge your thoughts because not all of our thoughts are true! As you write down your thoughts and the corresponding distortion, ask yourself: Is this really true? Do I know this to be true, for sure? Have I checked the facts?
        \n\nTake a step back and assess the situation again. Continue challenging your thinking with other questions such as Am I really a bad person? or Could it be that she was doing the best she could and just made a mistake? or When would this not be true?
        \n\n<b>Step 3: Compassionate Self-talk </b>
        \n\nWe are often extremely hard on ourselves. Our self-talk is harsh, negative, and sometimes abusive.  When you think about how you would speak to a good friend, chances are you\’d never say the things you say to yourself to your friend.
        \n\nFor each distortion you\’ve identified, write down how you would respond to a good friend. Then, practice using this more compassionate self-talk with yourself.
        \n\n<b>Step 4: Seek Support</b>
        \n\nFind a friend or someone you trust to help you challenge your assumptions and distortions. The right questions can help you shift your perspective from black or white to shades of grey! Creating some flexibility in your thinking can help you lower your stress, feel less anxious and shift away from depression.
        \n\n<b>Step 5: Positive/Negative Outcomes</b>
        \n\nSelf-assessment is key to finding the mental and emotional freedom you\’re looking for as you challenge your own cognitive distortions. By asking yourself to assess the positive and negative outcome of sticking with your perspective, you\’re able to decide whether it\’s worth keeping or changing it.
    </string>
    <string name="course2day3"><b>What can you do if you feel as though you are engaging in self-destructive behaviors?</b>
        \n\n1. Start by identifying the behaviors in your life that you feel are getting in the way of reaching your goals. Insight is an integral part of changing your behavior.
        \n\n2. Get real. Find ways to stop minimizing these unhealthy behaviors and rationalizing their presence. Examine how a behavior really impacts your life.
        \n\n3. Don\’t get down on yourself. Being overly critical of yourself or thinking that you are weak creates a worse self-concept, often leading lower self-esteem and confidence.
        \n\n4. Make it harder to act impulsively. Do you find that you over eat when you are stressed? Keep foods that you tend to binge on out of the house. Do you overspend when you are sad? Only withdraw enough cash for your weekly expenses and make access to your debit/credit cards more difficult.
        \n\n5. Practice mindfulness. Focusing on the present can help you to more readily identify your emotions and the behaviors that are getting in the way of your goals.
        \n\n6. Start to self-reflect. Journaling or keeping a daily log of healthy habits can be a great way to build positive patterns of behavior.
        \n\n7. Seek professional help. Meeting with a counselor or psychologist can be an important part of reducing unhealthy behaviors. A psychologist can help you to identify triggers that lead to your self-defeating behaviors and provide tools to help you replace them with healthier options.
    </string>
    <string name="course2day4"><b>What is Assertiveness?</b>
        \n\nAssertiveness is the quality of being self-assured and confident without being aggressive. In the field of psychology and psychotherapy, it is a skill that can be learned and a mode of communication.
        \n\n<b>Benefits of Being Assertive</b>
        \n\nBeing assertive allows you to communicate your wants and needs more authoritatively, while remaining fair and empathetic. It can also help you to become more self-confident, and even improve your mental health.
        \n\nAssertiveness provides several other benefits that can help you both in your workplace and in other areas of your life. In general, assertive people:
        \n\n<b>1. Make Great Managers.</b>
        \n\nThey get things done by treating people with fairness and respect, and are treated by others the same way in return. This means that they are often well-liked and seen as leaders that people want to work with.
        \n\n<b>2. Negotiate Successful Solutions.</b>
        \n\nThey are able to recognize the value of their opponent\'s position and can quickly find common ground with them.
        \n\n<b>3. Are Better Doers and Problem Solvers.</b>
        \n\nThey feel empowered to do whatever it takes to find the best solution to the problems that they encounter.
        \n\n<b>4. Are Less Anxious and Stressed.</b>
        \n\nThey are self-assured and don\'t feel threatened or victimized when things don\'t go as planned or as expected.
        \n\n<b>5. Have Greater Job Satisfaction.</b>
        \n\nThey feel confident to say <b>yes</b> to the person and <b>no</b> to the task, and maintain boundaries.
    </string>
    <string name="course2day5"><b>Identifying Good Points</b>
        \n\nIn order to identify your good qualities ask these questions to yourself for self awareness:
        \n\n1. What do you like about yourself?
        \n\n2. What have you achieved in life? However small?
        \n\n3. What challenges have you faced in life?
        \n\n4. What skills have you acquired?
        \n\n5. What do other people value in you?
        \n\n6. What qualities do you value in others that you have?
        \n\n7. What small positives are you discounting?
        \n\n8. What are the bad qualitites that you don\'t have?
        \n\n<b>Noticing Your Positive Qualities</b>
        \n\n1. Get into habit of noticing your positive qualities and strengths.
        \n\n2. Look out for these in everyday events.
        \n\n3. Keep a note of these in a diary.
    </string>
    <string name="course2day6"><b>Tips For Building and Maintaining Positive Self Esteem</b>
    \n\n<b>1. Don\’t Compare Yourself to Others</b>
        \n\nOne of the first and most important steps to achieving a positive self-outlook is to stop comparing yourself to others. You can only work with what you have – and that is probably a lot, so stop focusing on what others have and focus on what YOU have and embrace it. When comparing yourself to others, you never know what could be going on behind-the-scenes – remember the grass isn\’t always greener.
        \n\n<b>2. Identify Your Strengths and Areas For Opportunity</b>
        \n\nIf you are not feeling as confident or positive about certain aspects of your life, it\’s time to determine why. By creating a list of your strengths and areas for improvement you can bring to the forefront all of the positive qualities about yourself, while identifying areas you can work on. It\’s important to be aware of the language you use when identifying areas of improvement. Maybe you would like to improve your physical fitness, saying I’m fat, creates a negative tone. Instead, under areas for opportunity say focus more on physical health or visit the gym twice a week.
        \n\n<b>3. Be Open To Change</b>
        \n\nAs you work on embracing your strengths and working on areas for improvement, it\’s important to update your list of areas for opportunity as you grow and change. Making the list is one thing- but being motivated to put in the work and make the change is another. Don\’t give up! Turn your fear or reservations into motivation and remember you are putting in the effort for a great cause.
        \n\n<b>4. Be Realistic</b>
        \n\nChange is not something that happens overnight, and perfection doesn\’t exist. You\’re working to be the best version of yourself and the person who identifies the best version is YOU. Also consider that everyone makes mistakes. If you experience a set-back don\’t beat yourself up about it, learn from it and move on.
        \n\n<b>5. Surround Yourself With A Support Squad</b>
        \n\nThe people who love and care about you will be your biggest support system in your journey to positive self-worth. Surround yourself with people who invigorate and energize you and make you feel positive about reaching your goals.
    </string>
    <string name="course3day1"><b>What is Sleep?</b>
        \n\nSleep is a naturally recurring state of mind and body, characterized by altered consciousness, relatively inhibited sensory activity, reduced muscle activity and inhibition of nearly all voluntary muscles during rapid eye movement sleep, and reduced interactions with surroundings.
        \n\n<b>The Importance of Getting Enough Sleep</b>
        \n\nFor most adults, at least seven hours of sleep each night is needed for proper cognitive and behavioral functions. An insufficient amount of sleep can lead to serious repercussions. Some studies have shown sleep deprivation leaves people vulnerable to attention lapses, reduced cognition, delayed reactions, and mood shifts.
        \n\nIt\’s also been suggested that people can develop a sort of tolerance to chronic sleep deprivation. Even though their brains and bodies struggle due to lack of sleep, they may not be aware of their own deficiencies because less sleep feels normal to them. Additionally, lack of sleep has been linked to a higher risk for certain diseases and medical conditions. These include obesity, type 2 diabetes, high blood pressure, heart disease, stroke, poor mental health, and early death.
        \n\nAdults who do not receive a sufficient amount of sleep each night can implement some positive lifestyle and sleep habits in order to log the needed seven to nine hours. These include the following:
        \n\n<b>1. Establish a realistic bedtime and stick to it every night, even on the weekends.</b>
        \n\n<b>2. Maintain comfortable temperature settings and low light levels in your bedroom.</b>
        \n\n<b>3. Keep a comfortable sleep environment by ensuring you have the best mattress, best pillows, and best sheets for your sleep preferences and body type.</b>
        \n\n<b>4. Consider a screen ban on televisions, computers and tablets, cell phones, and other electronic devices in your bedroom.</b>
        \n\n<b>5. Abstain from caffeine, alcohol, and large meals in the hours leading up to bedtime.</b>
        \n\n<b>6. Refrain from using tobacco at any time of day or night.</b>
        \n\n<b>7. Exercise during the day; this can help you wind down in the evening and prepare for sleep.</b>
    </string>
    <string name="course3day2"><b>What is Sleep Hygiene?</b>
    \n\nSleep hygiene refers to healthy habits, behaviours and environmental factors that can be adjusted to help you have a good night\'s sleep. Some sleeping problems are often caused by bad sleep habits reinforced over years or even decades. Improved sleep will not happen as soon as changes are made.
        \n\n<b>How Do You Practice Good Sleep Hygiene?</b>
        \n\n<b>1. Set Your Sleep Schedule</b> - Having a set schedule normalizes sleep as an essential part of your day and gets your brain and body accustomed to getting the full amount of sleep that you need.
        \n\n<b>2. Follow a Nightly Routine</b> - How you prepare for bed can determine how easily you’ll be able to fall asleep. A pre-sleep playbook including some of these tips can put you at ease and make it easier to get to fall asleep when you want to.
        \n\n<b>3. Cultivate Healthy Daily Habits</b> - It’s not just bedtime habits that play a part in getting good sleep. Incorporating positive routines during the day can support your circadian rhythm and limit sleep disruptions.
        \n\n<b>4. Optimize Your Bedroom</b> - A central component of sleep hygiene beyond just habits is your sleep environment. To fall asleep more easily, you want your bedroom to emanate tranquility.
    </string>
    <string name="course3day3"><b>Targeting Your Ideal Bedtime</b>
        \n\nCreating your ideal bedtime significantly increases the chances you\’ll get both the quantity and the quality of sleep you need.
        \n\nYou may be unsure about the right bedtime, but you\’re likely to know exactly what your wake time needs to be. That\’s because most people have what I call a socially determined wake up time. There is some external commitment—caring for a child, getting ready for work or school, getting the dog outside—that dictates when we must wake and begin our day. Most of us do not have a wake time that is wholly within our control. Bedtime, on the other hand, offers us much more discretion and freedom. In order to set your ideal bedtime, you\’ll start by using your wake time.
        \n\n<b>Sleep Goals</b>
        \n\nIn creating a nightly sleep routine and an ideal bedtime, you’re working to meet a couple fundamental sleep goals: getting enough sleep, and making sure it is high-quality rest. My two-part sleep calculator will help you do both. This simple sleep calculator uses information about your sleep cycle to get sufficient rest, maintain healthy circadian and sleep-wake rhythms, and wake naturally feeling refreshed and ready to begin your day.
        \n\n<b>Ideal Bedtime Sleep Calculator</b>
        \n\nThis formula tackles sleep quantity. The only information you need is your wake-up time. Here’s how it works:
        \n\n<b>1. The average sleep cycle is 90 minutes long</b>
        \n\n<b>2. A typical night of sleep includes 5 full sleep cycles</b>
        \n\n<b>3. 90 x 5 = 450 minutes, or 7.5 hours</b>
        \n\n<b>4. Starting at your wake time, work back 7.5 hours to find your bedtime</b>
        \n\nFor example: You need to wake at 6 a.m. to get ready for work. Counting back 7.5 hours, your ideal bedtime is 10:30 p.m. That means lights out, in bed, ready for sleep at that time.
        \n\nThis bedtime is a starting point, and may need some adjustment, as individual sleep cycles vary in their duration. Try your new bedtime for a week. The goal is to wake naturally about 5-10 minutes ahead of your alarm. If you find yourself waking significantly ahead of your alarm, move your bedtime slightly later. If after a week, you\’re still sleeping right through to your alarm, you need to shift your bedtime earlier. Do so in 15-minute increments until you\’re waking naturally just before your alarm.
        \n\n<b>Not Just More Sleep, But Better</b>
        \n\nThe Ideal Bedtime sleep calculator takes care of sleep quantity. But what about sleep quality? Sleep quality is achieved by sustained rest, with sufficient time spent in each of the four sleep stages—Stages 1-3 and REM sleep—to maintain physical and mental health and function.
        \n\nSleep efficiency is one important measure of sleep quality used by sleep scientists and physicians. There\’s an easy, low-tech way to measure sleep efficiency that requires no sleep tracking devices or equipment. You need only a few basic pieces of information about your night of sleep:
        \n\n<b>1. The total amount of time you spend in bed sleeping or trying to sleep between bedtime and waking</b>
        \n\n<b>2. How long it takes you to fall asleep</b>
        \n\n<b>3. The amount of time you spent awake during the night</b>
        \n\nLet\’s say you spent a total of 7 hours, or 420 minutes, in bed last night. It took you 25 minutes to fall asleep. You spent another 25 minutes awake throughout the night, a result of three separate periods of wakefulness.
        \n\nHere\’s how to calculate your sleep efficiency for this night:
        \n\n<b>1. Total sleep time: 420 minutes</b>
        \n\n<b>2. Minus time to fall asleep: 25 minutes</b>
        \n\n<b>3. Minus total time spent awake: 25 minutes</b>
        \n\n<b>4. Actual time spent sleeping: 370 minutes (6 hours, 10 minutes)</b>

    </string>
    <string name="course3day4"><b>Why Your Thoughts Race at Night></b>
        \n\nSome people who experience racing thoughts at night also experience racing or anxious thoughts during the day. But many people also have the experience of feeling relatively calm during the day, only to find that their thoughts start to race as soon as they try falling asleep.
        \n\nThe reason for this is that most of us are more easily distracted from our worries and fears during the day. We are working, caring for others, indulging in screen time, and moving rapidly from one activity to another, barely aware of our interior emotional experience. But when everything goes dark and quiet at night, we find ourselves alone with our thoughts, and the darker, more difficult emotions and worries tend to present themselves.
        \n\n<b>What Do Racing Thoughts at Night Feel Like?</b>
        \n\nRacing thoughts are thoughts that come on suddenly and seem to populate your mind without you being able to control them. Some common experiences include:
        \n\n<b>1. A list of thoughts that stream through your mind on a loop</b>
        \n\n<b>2. The feeling that you are watching different thoughts and scenarios play themselves in your mind, as if on a movie reel</b>
        \n\n<b>3. The thoughts seem to come in quick succession, as though someone is talking too fast inside your head</b>
        \n\n<b>4. You may also be experiencing other signs of anxiety that accompany these racing thoughts, such as a racing heartbeat, sweating, or sped up breathing</b>
        \n\n<b>What Causes Racing Thoughts at Night?</b>
        \n\nLife stressors—such as job stress, familial stress, financial stress, or experiencing a major life transition—is the most frequent cause of racing thoughts at night. This is likely the cause if the experience of racing thoughts at night is new to you, and can be traced to a new stressor or stressful event.
        \n\n<b>1. Life Stresses and Transitions</b>
        \n\nPeople who have anxiety tend to have more trouble sleeping and may experience racing thoughts at night. Panic disorder also makes you more likely to experience this. Sometimes racing thoughts at night resemble symptoms of a panic attack.
        \n\n<b>Bipolar Disorder</b>
        \n\nRacing thoughts are one of the characteristics of bipolar disorder, especially during a manic episode. However, simply having racing thoughts does not mean you have bipolar disorder. Bipolar disorder has other attributes as well, including intense mood fluctuations, engaging in risky behavior, and experiencing delusions or hallucinations. Bipolar disorder requires a proper diagnosis from a doctor or psychiatrist.
        \n\n<b>Obsessive Compulsive Disorder</b>
        \n\nPeople who experience obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) may have racing thoughts. Usually, nighttime isn\’t the only time that people with OCD experience racing thoughts. Obsessive thoughts, compulsions, and fixations on things like order and cleanliness are other common characteristics of OCD.
        \n\n<b>Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)</b>
        \n\nExperiencing a trauma, either recently or years ago, can cause post-traumatic stress disorder. Symptoms of the disorder include racing thoughts, including at night. In this case, you may fixate on the traumatic event that happened to you, and experience flashbacks to it.
        \n\n<b>Medications</b>
        \n\nCertain prescribed medications, either for mental health or to treat a medical condition, can cause racing thoughts and insomnia. If you have recently started a new medication and have found that the racing thoughts at night correlate with this, talk to your doctor about potential side effects and alternative medications.
        \n\n<b>Tips for Coping With Racing Thoughts at Night</b>
        \n\nFor many of us, making a few life changes and adopting some healthy habits to cope with stress, can help reduce or eliminate nighttime ruminations and insomnia. Here are some tips.
        \n\n<b>Keep a Worry Journal</b>
        \n\nWriting down some of your thoughts and fears before you go to bed can be therapeutic and can help reduce nighttime stress. Often, our stressful thoughts boil to the surface at night, but they are still in our heads the rest of the day. Having an outlet to let them all out when it\’s not late at night can really help:
        \n\n1. Get a notebook and label it worry journal
        \n\n2. Take 5-10 minutes a day to list your worries
        \n\n3. Or, spend 5-10 minutes doing some freewriting about whatever thoughts come to mind
        \n\n<b>Meditation</b>
        \n\nMeditation, either right before bed, or sometime during the day, can have a strong impact on your ability to fall asleep without overwhelming thoughts
        \n\n1. If this is your first time adopting a meditation practice, keep it simple.
        \n\n2. You can start with just a few minutes a day, and then go from there.
        \n\n3. If you need help, there are several apps on the market that will guide you in a meditation.
        \n\n4. There is no right way to meditate; just closing your eyes in silence for a few minutes a day is enough.
        \n\n5. You might find that your thoughts race while you meditate, but meditation is an opportunity to learn to watch your thoughts go by more mindfully, and learn to let them go.
        \n\n<b>Decrease Screen Time Before Bed</b>
        \n\nMany of us are addicted to our screens, and stay on them all day, through bedtime. Unfortunately, these habits have a tendency to wreak havoc on our ability to fall asleep easily and can cause us to have a racing mind at the end of the day. Additionally, too much screen time before bed, along with blue light emitted from screens, can cause a decrease in melatonin levels, which can make it more difficult to fall asleep.
        \n\n<b>Be Mindful of Your Evening Media Consumption</b>
        \n\nWatching scary TV or movies, or reading disturbing books right before bed, can impact our sleep, and cause racing thoughts. Many of us have become addicted to doomscrolling, too, feeling compelled to keep up with upsetting world events and news items.
        \n\n<b>Address Your Life Stressors</b>
        \n\nSome aspects of life are out of our control, and these situations can contribute to heightened stress and anxiety, along with insomnia. But sometimes, experiencing something like racing thoughts before bed can be looked at as a wake-up call to make some life changes to reduce stress.
        \n\nMaybe it\’s time to leave a toxic job. Maybe you need to address the dysfunction in one of your primary relationships. Feel empowered to make the changes that will allow you to live a healthier, less stressful life.
    </string>
    <string name="course3day5">Review</string>
    <string name="healthpointsdesc">Health points allows the patient to understand the depression severity and it is shown on a scale of 27. \nThen answers are marked on a scale of 0-4 and then all the answers are added to get the score.
        \n\nIt is not a screening tool for depression but it is used to monitor the severity of depression and response to treatment.


    </string>
</resources>